The true story of how a few brave souls saved the lives of thousands.
Nanking is a documentary, drama, history film directed by Bill Guttentag.
The story of the rape of Nanking, one of the most tragic events in history.
In 1937, the invading Japanese army murdered over 200,000
and raped tens of thousands of Chinese.
In the midst of this horror, a small group of Western
expatriates banded together to save 250,000.
Nanking shows the tremendous impact individuals
can make on the course of history.
John Magee, played by Hugo Armstrong.
Chang Yu Zheng, played by Rosalind Chao.
Lewis Smythe, played by Stephen Dorff.
George Fitch, played by John Getz.
Minnie Vautrin, played by Mariel Hemingway.
Yang Shu Ling, played by Michelle Krusiec.
Nanking (Chinese: 南京) is a 2007 documentary film about the Nanjing Massacre, committed
in 1937 by the Japanese army in the former capital city Nanjing, China.
It was inspired by Iris Chang's book The Rape of Nanking (1997), which discussed the persecution and murder of the Chinese by the
Imperial Japanese Army in the then-capital of Nanjing at the outset of the Second Sino-Japanese War (1937–45).
The film draws on letters and diaries from the era as well as archive footage and
interviews with surviving victims and perpetrators of the massacre.
Contemporary actors play the roles of the Western missionaries, professors, and businessmen who
formed the Nanking Safety Zone to protect the city's civilians from Japanese forces.
Particular attention is paid to Nazi Party member John Rabe, a German
businessman who organized the Nanking Safety Zone, Robert O.
Wilson, a surgeon who remained in Nanjing to care for legions of victims, and Minnie
Vautrin, a missionary educator who rendered aid to thousands of Nanjing's women.
The film explores themes of rescue, rape, chinese
woman, nanking massacre china 1937, 1930s.
The tone is emotional.